Nathan Schneider

Web Developer

Links

Portfolio

http://nschneider.info

GitHub

https://github.com/nathanlschneider

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathanlschneider

Contact

Address

22 Brookmeadow N Ln SW Apt 3

Grandville, MI 49418

Phone

(616) 803-9803

E-mail

nlschneider@gmail.com

Experienced Developer with a demonstrated history of creating solutions for customer needs. **Passionate** about coding and adhering to best practices to maintain quality work, in both team and individual environments. **Committed** to continuous growth by learning and using the latest web technologies, and sharing knowledge with peers to achieve success.

Skills

Front-End	Back-End		Source Control	UI / UX
Javascript	REST / API	MongoDB	Git	Figma
CSS / SCSS	Node	SQL	Github	Prototyping
HTML	Express	Shell Script	Agile	GIMP
XALA	Linux			RWD
React / JSX	NPM			

Experience

2015-09 IT Support & Development

Bootstrap

Meritage Hospitality Group

Ivanti Service Manager Administration & Development

C# / VB.NET

Full Stack Web Development

Workday Integration

Aloha POS Systems Support

2013-01 - Remote Service Technician - Level II

2015-08 Support.com

Level II Home Networking Support (HNS) for Comcast

Education

2011 - Grand Rapids Community College

2014 IT - Systems Administration

CIS - Computer Programming

Certificates

2018-03 ASD.1x: Agile Software Development

https://courses.edx.org/certificates/04f2056115074150927839bf407ffa85

2018-08 Web Developer Bootcamp

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-JZ7LBJDJ/

Courses

Advanced Visual Basic.NET Programming CO 225

Advanced Windows Operating System CO 205

C++ Programming CO 127

HTML Essentials CO 148

Internet Scripting CO 247

Introduction to C# Programming CO 129

Introduction to Computer Information Systems CO 110

Local Area Networking CO 233

Principles of Information Security CO 212

UNIX Operating System CO 132

UNIX Shell Programming CO 142

UNIX/LINUX Systems Administration CO 232

Visual Basic.NET Programming CO 124

Web Design Fundamentals CO 146

Wide Area Networking (WAN) Theory CO 231

Projects

pm2Mon

Web GUI

This is a simple Web GUI for the pm2 Node process monitor. It's currently using vanilla HTML/CSS/JS, along with Node and Express to poll and serve data. I plan on redoing this in React.

Github https://github.com/nathanlschneider/pm2Mon **Demo** http://nschneider.info:8989

Cradlepoint Watcher

Realtime LTE Monitor

This App monitors the WAN/LTE status of several hundred Cradlepoint WIFI Routers deployed at several Wendy's locations across the country. It uses React on the front end and Node, Express, Web Sockets, and MongoDB on the backend. It's allowed the company to track LTE usage and save money on unnecessary LTE costs.

Github https://github.com/nathanlschneider/react-cradlepoint_watcher

Ticket Viewer

IvantiSM Web App

This is a companion progressive web app for IvantiSM to view Help Desk incident tickets on mobile devices. It was written with vanilla HTML/CSS/JS. It's being used by operations and IT employees at a Wendy's Franchisee. Google's Lighthouse was used to make sure 100% PWA functionality.

Github https://github.com/nathanlschneider/ticket_viewer **Demo** https://bit.ly/2Mj7uvH

Portfolio

My Web Portfolio

This is the code for my personal/portfolio website. It was built using React and Node. It's fully responsive with fluid typography.

Github https://github.com/nathanlschneider/portfolio-final **Demo** http://nschneider.info